# 哈喽 大家好
Hello everyone.
# 今天我要上去弄一下上面的竹叶
Today I am going up there to clean up the bamboo leaves
# 然后再把我们那个梨 已经这么大了用纸包起来
And then take our pears, they are like this big now, I am covering them up with paper bags.
# 要不然那些小鸟几下就给它吃掉了
Otherwise the birds will eat the pears very quickly.
# 第一次上去还多害怕
I was a little scared the first time I climbed up here.
# 扫不扫哦
Are we sweeping the roof?
# 要扫
Yes.
# 既然上去了肯定要扫了
Of course, he is sweeping it, he climbed up there after all.
# 吓我一跳 差点滑了
I almost slipped and got scared a little.
# 现在终于上来了 用我四伯爷给我的这个袋子
Now that I am up here, using the bags my uncle gave me,
# 然后把这个梨全部套起来
To cover all the pears.
# 这个鸟啊 梨小的时候它不吃
These birds do not eat the pears when they are small.
# 就是专门等到它长到半大不熟的时候吃得干干净净的
Birds purposely wait until the pears grow half way through, then they will eat all the pears.
# 上都上来了然后我先把这个竹叶扫一下
Since I am up here, I am going to sweep the bamboo leaves.
# 这个竹叶太多了
There are too many bamboo leaves up here.
# 打击看一下这个梨 这个已经很大个了
Take a look at this pear, it is pretty big now.
# 已经这么大了
It has grown a lot.
# 这现在就是小鸟要吃的时候了
This is the time when birds are going to eat the pears.
# 这个已经被梨压下来了 等一下我用一个（袋子）
Now the weight of the pears is pulling the branch down, I am going to use (a bag to collect them)
# 掉了一个
One fell off
# 都已经这么大太可惜了
It grew pretty big, what a pity.
# 待会儿用个东西把它撑起来
I am going to find something up hold it up.
# 这个掉在上面已经烂了这个
When it fell, it got rotten on the roof.
# 太可惜了
Such a waste.
# 这个都已经烂了
This one rotted.
# 梨太多了把这个压垮了
There are too many pears up here and the weight is holding down the branches.
# 废了九牛二虎之力把这个上面又扫了
It took so much effort to sweep the roof again.
# 我估计十天半个月之后又是一层
I think after a couple of weeks later it will be full of bamboo leaves again.
# 现在我来包一下这个梨
Now I am going to cover the pears.
# 有没有懂行的 来教我一下
Is there any expert, can you teach me a little?
# 这个位置
Put it here?
# 嗯 可以了
Yes, sure.
# 有没有懂行的教我一下这个怎么弄
Is there any expert, please teach me how to do this?
# 在我没学会之前先让它这样子吧
Before I learned how to handle it, I will just leave it like this.
# 这个撑哪里 撑这里差不多
Where do I put this one? Should I put it here?
# 可以
Okay this is good.
# 这边再给它撑一个就差不多了
Then I will put another one here, it should fine now.
# 好
Okay
# 这个给它打开
Now I am opening this bag.
# 这给它打开 然后把这个果子放进去
Open the bag then put the pear into the bag.
# 然后这样子收这个 收收收
And then wrap it up and pinch together the edges.
# 收到这里的时候这有一根铁丝
At the end I will tie it up with iron wire.
# 把它这样子捆起来捏紧就可以了 特别简单
Wrap up the edge and pinch the wire, then I am done. Very simple.
# 一次装它两个 让它们有伴 稍微捏一下就可以了
I am bagging these two together, so they can keep each other company, just slightly pinch it.
# 这样鸟儿就不知道里面有梨 它就吃不到了
This way, the birds do not know there are pears in there, they cannot eat them
# 这里还有
There are more here.
# 大家可以看一下这里上面有2个 这就是被鸟儿吃掉的
Let take a look at the two up there, the birds ate them.
# 可能说这个鸟儿想留着下一次来吃其它的
May the birds want to come back and eat other pears.
# 我这次就把它包起来
But I will cover the pears this time.
# 哇这个上面 一枝上面结4个
Wow there are 4 pears on this branch.
# 这个你搞得我好为难啊
What should I do with it?
# 我这么接呢
How do I cover it?
# 它们4个包在一起 4兄弟很棒
I will jut bag four of them together, four siblings, very nice.
# 去年这个（树）上面都只长了几个
Last year, this(tree) only had a few pears.
# 刚好要吃的时候就被鸟吃了
Birds ate most of the pears when they were about to ripe.
# 今年给它保护一下
This year I am providing protection for the pears.
# 这个是掉在那个（雨棚）上面
This one fell on top of that(shed).
# 被掉下来的竹叶捂在一起捂烂了 太可惜了丢掉
These pears were covered by the bamboo leaves fallen from trees and got rotten, I have to throw them away, what a waste.
# 把这个没烂的也包一下
I am going to cover this one that is not rotten.
# OK
Okay
# 这边可能它会烂就留点给鸟吃
If it is partially rotten, then I will just leave it to birds.
# 这几个特别漂亮
These pears look very nice.
# 先包这两个
I am covering these two.
# 然后再包这两个
Then covering these two.
# 哟 还包不住它啊
Oops, it does not fit the pear.
# OK 可以了
Okay, this is good.
# 好 那些包不到的不整了 不关事
The ones are too far to reach, you do not need to cover them.
# 那儿不好弄得 我逮要把它逮下来
It is not easy to reach the, I will try to pull them down.
# 我看一下拉不拉得下来
Let me see if I can get it down.
# 我四伯爷说的就这三个
These are the three my uncle was talking about.
# 哎呦 包的不是很好 希望鸟吃不到
I did not cover it well so I hope the birds cannot reach it.
# 看一下 我给你们看一下这个被鸟吃掉的
Here, let me show you the one that got eaten by the birds.
# 看到没这个给它吃空了
Can you the inside is hollow, all eaten by the birds.
# 这边是很好看的
On this side, it looks nice.
# 浪费
Wasteful
# 好 本期视频就到这里 拜拜
Okay this is the end of the video, bye bye.
# 我要下去了
I am going down now.